Milislav Demerec Papers 1919-1966 Mss.B.D394
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Reddick, Donald, n.d.; 1 item (Box 19)
  - Registrar. Radcliffe College, 1944; 1 item (Box 19)
  - Renner, O., 1928; 1 item (Box 19)
  - Resende, Flavio, 1947; 19 items (Box 19)
  - Revici, Emanuel, Cancer Research and Hospital Foundation, 1955; 7 items (Box 20)
  - Reviews, 1961-1965; 6 items (Box 20)
  - Rhoades, Marcus M., 1931-1939; 26 items (Box 20)
    Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Columbia University; Emerson, Rollins Adams; Publication; Zea (maize) genetics
  - Richey, Fred D., 1923-1933; 19 items (Box 20)
  - Riddle, Oscar, 1960; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Rienicha, G., 1930; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Riley, Francis, n.d.; 0 items (Box 20)
  - Riley, Herbert P., 1947-1954; 4 items (Box 20)
  - Robbins, William Jacob, 1934-1952; 8 items (Box 20)
  - Robertson, C. W., 1938; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1944; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Rockefeller Institute, 1959; 4 items (Box 20)
  - Rodbord, Joseph Harrison, 1933; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Rodriguez, Juan De G., 1925; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Roman, Herschel, 1957; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Ronto, E., 1924; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Roper, J. Alan, 1960; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Roscoe B. Jackson Memorial Laboratory, 1953; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Rosin, S., 1946; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Rosner, Lee, 1962; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Rünnstrom, John, 1946; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Russell, William L., 1947; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Ryan, Francis F., 1956-1960; 6 items (Box 20)
  - St. Pierre, Marie L., 1964; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Sanderson, Kenneth E., 1963-1966; 28 items (Box 20)
  - Sapehin, A. A., 1932-1933; 3 items (Box 20)
  - Sax, Karl, 1931-1944; 6 items (Box 20)
  - Scandalios, John C., 1960-1964; 14 items (Box 20)
  - Schafler, S., 1963; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Schager, Franz., 1946; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Schick, R., 1930; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Schiemann, E., 1928-1929; 5 items (Box 20)
  - Schmidt, F., 1957; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Schnueck, Laurine, 1930; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Schoenheimer, Rudolf, 1939; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Schrader, Franz, 1929-1937; 19 items (Box 20)
  - Schramm, J. R., 1923-1960; 17 items (Box 20)
  - Schultz, Jack, 1934-1954; 23 items (Box 20)
    Drosophila genetics; Drosophila Information Service; Genetics; Goldschmidt, Richard Benedict
  - Schulz, Robert F., 1945; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Schwemmle, N., 1931; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Schweitzer, Morton D., 1935; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Schwinck, Ilse, 1959; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Science, 1960; 3 items (Box 20)
  - Science Newsletter, 1956-1957; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Scientists' committee on loyalty problems, 1948-1965; 9 items (Box 20)
  - Senn, P. H., 1926; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Serban, Mihai, 1938; 3 items (Box 20)
  - Sermonti, Giuseppe, 1960; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Seyfried, Adam P., 1938; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Shapiro, Horace, 1937; 3 items (Box 20)
  - Sharp, Lester W., 1926; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Shibuya, Ryohitsu, 1956; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Shifriss, Oved, 1945; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Shipman, Emmet E., 1936; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Showalter, H. M., 1937; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Shull, A. Franklin, 1936; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Shull, George Harrison, 1920-1938; 2 folders (Box 20)
    International Congress of Genetics; Publication -- Genetics
    - Folder 1, 1920-1938; 27 items (Box 20)
    - Folder 2, 1923; 3 items (Box 20)
  - Singh, Gurmit, 1957; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Singleton, W. Ralph, 1943-1948; 3 items (Box 20)
  - Skipper, H. A., 1948; 1 item (Box 20)
  - Slavko, Troj, 1923-1924; 3 items (Box 20)
  - Slizynski, B. M., 1937-1951; 11 items (Box 20)
  - Smith, Derek A., 1961-1963; 17 items (Box 20)
  - Smith, Gilbert M., 1933; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Smith, Harold H., 1959; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Smith, Helen Berenice, 1930; 3 items (Box 20)
  - Smith, Thomas L., 1935-1936; 3 items (Box 20)
  - Snell, George D., 1935-1945; 3 items (Box 20)
  - Society for experimental biology and medicine, 1950; 2 items (Box 20)
  - Society of American bacteriologists, 1953-1954; 3 items (Box 20)
  - Sonneborn, T. M., 1947-1960; 6 items (Box 20)
  - Sonnenblick, B.P., 1937; 5 items (Box 20)
  - South America, 1958-1962; 2 folders (Box 20)
    Bacterial genetics; Educational matters; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
    - Folder 1, 1958-1959; 54 items (Box 20)
    - Folder 2, 1960-1962; 18 items (Box 20)
  - Souvenirs, 1919 ca.; 5 items (Box 20)
  - Spassry, B., 1948; 1 item (Box 21)
  - Speicher, B. R., 1936; 2 items (Box 21)
  - Spencer, Warren P., 1927-1941; 14 items (Box 21)
  - Speyer and Peters, 1920; 1 item (Box 21)
  - Spiegelman, S., 1948; 1 item (Box 21)
  - Spike, J. Edward, 1953; 1 item (Box 21)
  - Spoehr, H. A., 1932; 2 items (Box 21)
  - Sprague, George F., 1925-1930; 3 items (Box 21)
  - Sprague, Howard B., 1924; 1 item (Box 21)
  - Sprinson, D. B., 1963; 1 item (Box 21)
  - Srb, Adrian M., 1951-1962; 7 items (Box 21)
  - Stadler, L. J. (Lewis John), 1926-1949; 47 items (Box 21)
    Conferences and symposia; Genetics of plants -- Barley; Political issues; Radiation genetics; Recommendations; Zea (maize) genetics
  - Stampar, A., 1946-1957; 2 items (Box 21)
  - Stanley, Wendell M., 1940-1947; 3 items (Box 21)
  - Steggerda, Morris, 1936; 2 items (Box 21)
  - Steinbach, H. B., 1947; 2 items (Box 21)
  - Steinberg, Arthur G., 1937-1960; 4 items (Box 21)
  - Stent, Gunther S., 1955; 1 item (Box 21)
  - Stern, Curt, 1930-1955; 2 folders (Box 21)
    Biographical and personal data; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Conferences and symposia; Drosophila genetics; Drosophila Information Service; Fellowships, assistantships; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Publication
    - Folder 1, 1930-1935; 31 items (Box 21)
    - Folder 2, 1936-1955; 20 items (Box 21)
  - Stocker, Bruce A. D., 1956-1964; 10 items (Box 21)
  - Stone, Wilson, 1951; 2 items (Box 21)
  - Stowell, Robert E., 1947; 1 item (Box 21)
  - Straker, Robert L., 1940; 2 items (Box 21)
  - Streeter, George L., 1935-1937; 19 items (Box 21)
  - Striljkovic, Azunatci, 1928; 1 item (Box 21)
  - Stubbe, Hans H., 1948-1965; 23 items (Box 21)
  - Sturtevant, A. H. (Alfred Henry), 1926-1943; 2 folders (Box 21)
    Bridges, Calvin B.; Conferences and symposia; Drosophila genetics; Genetics of plants; Goldschmidt, Richard Benedict; Publication; Recommendations
    - Folder 1, 1926-1930; 14 items (Box 21)
    - Folder 2, 1931-1943; 31 items (Box 21)
  - Suivott, Gill, 1932; 1 item (Box 21)
  - Sun Radio Sound Studio, 1942-1944; 2 items (Box 21)
  - Suttle, A. D., 1923-1924; 3 items (Box 21)
  - Sutton, Eileen, 1943; 1 item (Box 21)
  - Suzuki, David, 1964-1965; 3 items (Box 21)
  - Svedrup, Harald U., 1949; 1 item (Box 21)
  - Sveshnikowa, Irene, 1933; 2 items (Box 21)
  - Swanson, C. P., 1958; 2 items (Box 21)
  - Szybalski, Waclaw, 1957-1964; 12 items (Box 21)
  - Tammes, Tines, 1934; 3 items (Box 21)
  - Tan, C. C., 1947; 5 items (Box 21)
  - Tatum, E. R., 1947-1959; 9 items (Box 21)
  - Tavcar, Alois, 1924-1960; 2 folders (Box 21)
    Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Honors; International Congress of Genetics; Russian politics and science; Zea (maize) genetics
    - Folder 1, 1924-1926; 6 items (Box 21)
    - Folder 2, 1931-1960; 29 items (Box 21)
  - Taylor, Austing L., 1966; 1 item (Box 21)
  - Taylor, C. V., 1935; 2 items (Box 21)
  - Teaching Scientist, 1949; 2 items (Box 21)
  - Teissier, Georges, 1947; 2 items (Box 21)
  - Tenney, Lloyd S., 1923; 1 item (Box 21)
  - Terada, Masanaka, 1956; 1 item (Box 21)
  - Thone, Frank, 1935-1947; 9 items (Box 21)
  - Tillyard, R. J., 1930; 2 items (Box 21)
  - Timofeeff-Resovsky, N. (Nikolai W.), 1930-1948; 2 folders (Box 21)
    Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Drosophila genetics; Drosophila Information Service; Fellowships, assistantships; International Congress of Genetics; Publication; Russian politics and science; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
    - Folder 1, 1930; 2 items (Box 21)
    - Folder 2, 1932-1948; 43 items (Box 21)
  - Timofeeff-Ressovsky, 1946; 1 item (Box 21)
  - Todorovica, 1923; 2 items (Box 21)
  - Tonnoir, A. L., 1930; 2 items (Box 21)
  - Towner, O. W., 1947; 1 item (Box 21)
  - Travel - Australia, 1961-1964; 2 folders (Box 22)
    Honors; International Congress of Genetics; Travel -- Australia; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
    - Folder 1, 1963-1964; 14 items (Box 22)
    - Folder 2, 1961-1963; 56 items (Box 22)
  - Travel - Yugoslavia, 1963; 31 items (Box 22)
    Honors; International Congress of Genetics; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; Travel -- Yugoslavia
  - Trelease, Sam F., 1937; 3 items (Box 22)
  - Tschermak, E., 1946; 1 item (Box 22)
  - Turesson, G., 1934-1943; 3 items (Box 22)
  - Turner, C. L., 1943; 2 items (Box 22)
  - Tuve, M. A. (Merle Antony), 1936-1940; 35 items (Box 22)
    Business; Carnegie Institution of Washington; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Drosophila genetics; Radiation genetics; Recommendations -- Fano, Ugo
  - Ultra-Violet rays, 1938-1940; 5 folders (Box 22)
    Hollaender, Alexander; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Radiation genetics; Research support
    - Folder 1, 1940; 34 items (Box 22)
    - Folder 2, 1940; 23 items (Box 22)
    - Folder 3, 1939-1940; 35 items (Box 22)
    - Folder 4, 1938-1939; 30 items (Box 22)
    - Folder 5, 1939; 26 items (Box 22)
  - Umbarger, H. Edwin, 1958; 2 items (Box 22)
  - Unidentified, 1924-1937; 19 items (Box 22)
  - Union of American Biological Societies, 1943-1952; 2 folders (Box 22)
    Business; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
    - Folder 1, 1945-1952; 9 items (Box 22)
    - Folder 2, 1943-1945; 48 items (Box 22)
  - Union of Soviet Socialist Republics, Embassy, 1945; 1 item (Box 22)
  - United Nations, 1948-1957; 6 items (Box 22)
  - United States. Dept. of Agriculture, 1927-1942; 6 items (Box 22)
  - Urey, Harold C., 1948; 2 items (Box 22)
  - Vaughan's Seed Store, 1956-1957; 3 items (Box 22)
  - Vejkovsky, Pavel, 1947; 3 items (Box 22)
  - Villee, Claude A., 1949; 3 items (Box 22)
  - Vilmorin, Roger de, 1930-1932; 4 items (Box 22)
  - Vogel, Henry J., 1960-1962; 3 items (Box 22)
  - Vogt, Martha, 1945; 2 items (Box 22)
  - Von Borstel, R. C., 1925-1960; 2 items (Box 22)
  - Vouk, V., 1928-1940; 9 items (Box 22)
  - W. Junk (?), 1925; 1 item (Box 22)
  - Waddington, C. H., 1938-1948; 8 items (Box 22)
  - Wagner, R. P., 1959-1960; 3 items (Box 22)
  - Wagner, Robert F., 1932; 1 item (Box 22)
  - Waksman, S. A., 1945-1952; 2 items (Box 22)
  - Wallace, Bruce, n.d.; 2 items (Box 22)
  - Wallace, Henry A., 1956; 5 items (Box 22)
  - War Research. Bacterial Resistance Project, 1939-1947; 47 items (Box 22)
    Bacterial genetics; Business; World War II -- Impact on science
  - Ward, H. B., 1934; 1 item (Box 22)
  - Ward, Katharine S., 1921; 1 item (Box 22)
  - Watanabe, Tsutomu, 1963; 3 items (Box 22)
  - Watkins, John, 1951; 2 items (Box 22)
  - Watson, Isabelle, 1924; 1 item (Box 22)
  - Weatherwax, Paul, 1932; 2 items (Box 22)
  - Weaver, Warren, 1936; 2 items (Box 22)
  - Weigel, Oswald, 1923-1926; 47 items (Box 22)
  - Weinstein, Alexander, 1926-1956; 7 items (Box 22)
  - Weiss, Freeman, 1924; 1 item (Box 22)
  - Welshons, W. J., 1957-1958; 3 items (Box 23)
  - Wenner-Gren Foundation, 1955; 2 items (Box 23)
  - Wenstrup, Edward J., 1937; 2 items (Box 23)
  - Wentz, John B., 1925-1933; 12 items (Box 23)
  - Werner, C. A., 1956; 2 items (Box 23)
  - Westergaard, M., 1947-1960; 20 items (Box 23)
  - Wettstein, Fritz V., 1939-1966; 3 items (Box 23)
  - White, M. J. D., 1937; 1 item (Box 23)
  - White, Orland E., 1925-1939; 6 items (Box 23)
  - Whiting, P. W., 1926-1944; 18 items (Box 23)
  - Whittinghill, Maurice, 1941-1947; 4 items (Box 23)
  - Wickler, Constance E., 1927; 2 items (Box 23)
  - Wiggans, R. G., 1925-1926; 3 items (Box 23)
  - Wilson, Carl L., 1953; 2 items (Box 23)
  - Wilson, E. B., 1934; 1 item (Box 23)
  - Wilson, J., n.d.; 1 item (Box 23)
  - Winge, O., 1958-1959; 6 items (Box 23)
  - Winkler, Hans, 1927; 1 item (Box 23)
  - Winsten, Jay, 1966; 3 items (Box 23)
  - Wirt, John L., 1924-1932; 5 items (Box 23)
  - Witschi, Emil, 1960; 2 items (Box 23)
  - Woods Hole Oceanographic Institute - Marine Biological Laboratory, 1944; 3 items (Box 23)
  - Woodward, Peter H., 1929; 3 items (Box 23)
  - Woodworth, C. M., 1924; 1 item (Box 23)
  - Work, Drs. T. S. and C. E., 1947; 2 items (Box 23)
  - World Population Conference, 1927; 1 item (Box 23)
  - Wright, Sewell, 1922-1939; 17 items (Box 23)
    Genetics; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
  - Wrinch, Dorothy M., 1936-1937; 3 items (Box 23)
  - Wyman, Harry B., 1957; 1 item (Box 23)
  - Yan, Yohoi, 1963; 2 items (Box 23)
  - Yanofsky, Charles, 1960; 2 items (Box 23)
  - Yugoslavinska Akademija Znanosti i Umjetnosti, 1926; 1 item (Box 23)
  - Yugoslavia, Consul General, 1960; 1 item (Box 23)
  - Yugoslavia. Encyclopedia, 1940; 6 items (Box 23)
  - Yura, Takashi, 1961-1962; 5 items (Box 23)
  - Zamenhof, Stephan, 1957; 2 items (Box 23)
  - Zanko, Vanja, 1946; 3 items (Box 23)
  - Zelle, Max R., 1957; 1 item (Box 23)
  - Zernik, Boris, 1924; 5 items (Box 23)
  - Zekitch, Fedor D., 1923-1924; 5 items (Box 23)
  - Zeleny, Charles, 1930-1933; 4 items (Box 23)
  - Zhebrak, A. R., 1945; 1 item (Box 23)
  - Zwilling, Edgar, 1959; 1 item (Box 23)
  - Zworykin, V. K., 1939-1940; 6 items (Box 23)
- Series II. Diplomas and awards, 1916-1966; 0.5 linear feet (Box 1)
  Miscellaneous diplomas and awards won by Demerec from throughout his career. Some items are rolled and stored separately at the end of the collection.
- Series III. Laboratory notes, ca.1930s-1940s; 1.5 linear feet
  Unsorted laboratory notes in Drosophila genetics, plant genetics, and penicillin research, dating primarily from the 1940s. The series includes a number of photographs and illustrations apparently ntended for publication.
  Bacterial genetics; Cancer, chemotherapy; Drosophila genetics; Genetics -- Mutable genes; Genetics -- Variegation; Genetics of plants; Genetics of plants -- Delphinium; Radiation genetics; Zea (maize) genetics
  - Unsorted research notes, ca.1930s-1940s (Box 1)
    Primarily relating to research on Drosophila, but including numerous photographs and other illustrations, probably intended for publication.
  - Unsorted research notes, 1941-1944 (Box 2)
    Data and notes pertaining to genetics of anitbiotic resistance in penicillin.
  - Unsorted research notes, ca.1930s-1940s (Box 3)
    Data and notes pertaining to Demerec's research on genetic mutants of Drosophila, x-ray induced mutagenesis, carcinogenesis, and penicillin.
- Series IV. Photographs, ca.1922-1960; 0.75 linear feet
  An important collection of photographs depicting Demerec, his fellow geneticists, and Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory. Among the more interesting photographic items are two albums of candid snapshots taken during the summer courses held at Cold Spring Harbor in 1942-1943, and two photo albums relating to his early genetic research on Delphinium and maize.
  - Milislav Demerec, bust, 3/4 profile, formal, [1935-1945]; Image: 25.5 x 19.3 cm, 1 photoprint
  - Milislav Demerec, half length, informal, seated at desk with pen in hand in front of file cabinet and bookcase, [1940-1950]; Image: 25.5 x 20 cm., 1 photoprint
  - Milislav Demerec with unidentified man, bust, informal, standing outside, Image: 20.5 x 25 cm., 1 photoprint
  - Milislav Demerec and Slavko (?) Borojevic, full length, informal, standing outside in front of building, 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - Milislav Demerec, identification photograph, bust, formal, 1948; Image: 55.5 x 5.2 cm., mount 26.5 x 20.5 cm., 1 photoprint; Carnegie Institution of Washington.
  - William Bateson with Rollins Adams Emerson, 3/4 length, informal, standing holding smoking pipes, 1922; Image: 25.5 x 20.3 cm., 1 photoprint
  - Erwin Baur, half length, 3/4 profile, seated with paper in hand, Image: 24.5 x 16.3 cm., 1 reproduction
  - Charles Benedict Davenport, bust, profile, informal, seated at desk writing, 1928; Image: 19 x 14 cm., 1 Photoprint
  - Charles Benedict Davenport, bust, profile, informal, seated at desk writing, 1928; Image: 19 x 14 cm., 1 Photoprint
  - Rollins Adams Emerson and Edward M. East, 3/4 length, informal seated, both holding papers, 1932; Image: 21 x 17.5 cm., 1 Photoprint
  - Cornell University, Department of Genetics, class group portrait, 1920; Image: 20.5 x 25 cm., 1 photoprint
  - Alfred Day Hershey, with dropper and beaker, at lab counter, 3/4 length portrait, ca. 1960; Image: 20.5 x 25 cm., 1 photoprint
  - Barbara McClintock, seated at laboratory table, examining maize, ca. 1960; Image: 20 x 25 cm., 1 photoprint
  - Thomas Hunt Morgan and Rollis Adams Emerson, 3/4 length portrait, ca. 1925; Image: 20.5 x 25 cm., 1 photoprint
  - Thomas Hunt Morgan and Rollis Adams Emerson, 3/4 length portrait, ca. 1930; Image: 20.5 x 25 cm., 1 photoprint
  - Thomas Hunt Morgan, portrait, ca.; Image: 11 x 19 cm., 1 photoprint
  - Marcus Morton Rhoades, 3/4 length portrait, ca. 1940; Image: 20.5 x 25 cm., 1 photoprint
  - International Congress of Genetics, 5th, Berlin, 1927, Image: 20.5 x 25 cm., 1 photoprint
  - International Congress of Genetics, 6th. Experimental station, Ithaca (New York), 1932; Image: 20.5 x 25 cm., 1 photoprint
  - International Congress of Genetics, 6th. Ithaca, 1932, 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait of nine men, sitting and standing, identified by text at the bottom of photograph as: C. C. Little; L. C. Dunn; D. F. Jones; M. Demerec; R. C. Cook; E. M. East; T. H. Morgan; C. B. Davenport; R. A. Emerson.
  - International Genetics Symposia, Tokyo and Kyoto, 1956, Image: 20.5 x 25 cm., 1 photoprint
  - International Genetics Symposia, Tokyo and Kyoto, 1956, Image: 20.5 x 25 cm., 1 photoprint
  - Carnegie Institution of Washington, Department of Genetics. Biological Conference, 1938, group portrait, Image: 20.5 x 25 cm., 1 photoprint
  - Carnegie Institution of Washington, Department of Genetics. Biological Conference, 1939, group portrait, Image: 20.5 x 25 cm., 1 photoprint
  - Carnegie Institution of Washington, Department of Genetics. Biological Conference, 1939, group portrait, Image: 20.5 x 25 cm., 2 photoprints
  - Symposium on the Immediate and Low-level Effects of Ionizing Radiation, Venice, July 1959. Lecture attendees, seated, Image: 20.5 x 25 cm., 1 photoprint
  - Symposium on the Immediate and Low-level Effects of Ionizing Radiation, Venice, July 1959. Milislav Demerec and undentified man, 3/4 length, leaning against table and talking, Image: 20.5 x 25 cm., 1 photoprint
  - Symposium on the Immediate and Low-level Effects of Ionizing Radiation, Venice, July 1959. Group walking along path, man in front taking photograph of photographer, Image: 20.5 x 25 cm., 1 photoprint
  - Symposium on the Immediate and Low-level Effects of Ionizing Radiation, Venice, July 1959. Group walking along path, man in front, Image: 20.5 x 25 cm., 1 photoprint
  - Carnegie Institution of Washington, Cold Spring Harbor, New York. Tissue culture group (portrait of members), 1959; Image: 20.5 x 25 cm., 1 photoprint
  - Milislav Demerec and four unidentified men, 3/4 length, informal, standing in laboratory at the Carnegie Institution of Washington, Cold Spring Harbor, Long Island, New York, Image: 21 x 25.5 cm., 1 photoprint; Gessling, Donald C
  - Milislav Demerec and unidentified men and women, 3/4 length, informal standing around table at the Carnegie Institution of Washington, Cold Springs Harbor, Long Island, New York, Image: 20.2 x 25.2 cm, 1 photoprint
  - Milislav Demerec, with unidentified seated woman, half length, informal, standing in laboratory at the Carnegie Institution of Washington, Cold Spring Habor, Long Island, New York, Image: 21 x 25.5 cm., 1 photoprint
  - Milislav Demerec, with 14 unidentified men and women, full length, informal, seated around a room at the Carnegie Institution of Science at Cold Spring Habor, Long Island, New York, Image: 20.5 x 25 cm., 1 photoprint; Medical Press, Inc
  - Milislav Demerec, with 14 unidentified men and women, full length, informal, seated around a room at the Carnegie Institution of Science at Cold Spring Habor, Long Island, New York, Image: 20.5 x 25 cm., 1 photoprint; Medical Press, Inc
  - Biological building at the Carnegie Institution of Washington, Cold Spring Harbour, Long Islnad, New York, n.d.; Image: 20.5 x 25.5 cm., 1 photoprint; Medical Press, Inc
  - Milislav Demerec, with 14 unidentified men and women, full length, informal, seated around a room at the Carnegie Institution of Science at Cold Spring Habor, Long Island, New York, Image: 20.5 x 25.5 cm., 1 photoprint; Medical Press, Inc
  - Aerial view of the Carnegie Institution of Washington, Cold Spring Harbor, Long Island, New York, Image: 13 x 20.5 cm., 1 photoprint
  - Carnegie Institution of Washington, Cold Spring Habor, Long Island, New York, landscape view, Image: 17 x 24.3 cm., 1 photoprint
  - Genetics Society of America, group portrait, standing outside of building at Woods Hole, Massachusetts, 1936; Image: 20.6 x 25.6 cm., 1 photoprint; Wood, Howard M
  - Genetics Society of America, group portrait, standing outside of building at Woods Hole, Massachusetts, 1936; Image: 20.6 x 25.6 cm., 1 photoprint; Wood, Howard M
  - Group portrait of scientists, including Milislav Demerec, formal, first row seated, second row standing, Image: 20.6 x 25.5 cm., 1 photoprint; Scott, Thomas F
  - Charles Davenport and unidentified man, full length, 3/4 profile, informal, standing outside, Image: 25 x 19.3 cm., 1 photoprint; Sunden Photo
  - Milislav Demerec, half length, formal, n.d.; Image: 17 x 12 cm., mount 28 x 21 cm., 1 Photoprint; Sunden Studio
  - Milislav Demerec, bust, formal, n.d.; Image: 17 x 12 cm., mount 29 x 20 cm., 1 Photoprint
  - Milislav Demerec, bust, formal, ca. 1922; Image: 24 x 17 cm., mount 31 x 21 cm., 1 Photoprint
  - Sewell Wright, half length, formal, n.d.; Image: 28 x 18 cm., 1 Photoprint; Edmonston
  - International Congress of Genetics, 8th, Stockholm, 1948, Image: 23 x 29 cm., 1 Photoprint
  - International Congress of Genetics, 8th, Stockholm, 1948, Image: 23 x 29 cm., 1 Photoprint
  - International Botanical Congress, 5th, Cambridge, Eng., 1930, Image: 23 x 29 cm., 1 Photoprint
  - Carnegie Institution of Washington, Biological buildings, n.d.; Image: 19 x 24 cm., 22 x 31 cm., 1 Photoprint
  - United States Atomic Energy Commission, meeting of the Bio-Medical Program Directors, 1962, Image: 22 x 28 cm., 1 Photoprint
  - Grave in Petrinja, Croatia, Yugoslavia, n.d.; Image: 12 x 17 cm., 23 x 30 cm., 1 Photoprint
  - Jacques Loeb, bust, formal, 1923; Image: 31 x 23 cm., 1 reproduction; Schmidt, Louis
  - Jacques Loeb, bust, formal, 1923; Image: 31 x 23 cm., 1 reproduction; Schmidt, Louis
  - Jacques Loeb, bust, formal, 1923; Image: 31 x 23 cm., 1 reproduction; Schmidt, Louis
  - Jacques Loeb, bust, formal, 1923; Image: 31 x 23 cm., 1 reproduction; Schmidt, Louis
  - Jacques Loeb, bust, formal, 1923; Image: 31 x 23 cm., 1 reproduction; Schmidt, Louis
  - Jacques Loeb, bust, formal, 1923; Image: 31 x 23 cm., 1 reproduction; Schmidt, Louis
  - Jacques Loeb, bust, formal, 1923; Image: 31 x 23 cm., 1 reproduction; Schmidt, Louis
  - Jacques Loeb, bust, formal, 1923; Image: 31 x 23 cm., 1 reproduction
  - Jacques Loeb, bust, formal, 1923; Image: 31 x 23 cm., 1 reproduction; Schmidt, Louis
  - Jacques Loeb, bust, formal, 1923; Image: 31 x 23 cm., 1 reproduction; Schmidt, Louis
  - Theodosius Dobzhansky and five other, full length, profile, informal, standing, Image: 15 x 21 cm., mount 18 x 29 cm., 1 Photoprint
  - Karl Ernst Von Baer, bust, 3/4 profile, formal, n.d.; Image: 28 x 23 cm., 1 Reproduction
  - M. (Milislav) Demerec at desk, Woods Hole, 1928; Image: 2.5 x 3, 1 photoprint
  - M. (Milislav) Demerec at desk, Woods Hole. Profile view, full image, Image: 3.75 x 4.75, 1 photoprint
  - M. (Milislav) Demerec Air Raid Warden I.D. card, Image: 1.25 x 1.25 photo on 2 x 4 card, 1photo I.d.